Nilesh Nimkar

DevOps Advocate, Cloud expert, Senior Release Engineer, IT Director/Lead

Nilesh.Nimkar@GMail.com

Summary

18+ years of engineering success and emerging technologies.

Skilled at launching new programs, training, establishing an infrastructure and leading projects to completion.

Excellent at leading and coaching teams and managing development of programs.

Talented at creating and maintaining stable build and release environments and keeping up-to-date with compliance regulations.

Experience

Senior Release Engineer at Interactive Data

June 2014 - Present

Consulting Release Architect via Open Systems Technologies at Deutsche Bank

April 2014 - June 2014 (3 months)

Established and implemented an enterprise level system to control meeting compliance

Verified compliance regulations were followed and upheld

Created a set of rules and guides for report system

Controlled and introduced the Build and Release systems

Produced consolidation programming plans and development

Maintained and controlled REST API plan for rules engine for consolidation of diverse VCS across the enterprise

Consulting Release Manager via Open Systems Technologies at Bridgewater Associates

June 2011 - March 2014 (2 years 10 months)

Key developer in testing, customizing, and implementing new programs

Led a team of 30+ developers, testers and operation support.

Created an automation procedure for applications

Introduced and facilitated outsourcing

Managed the changes, configurations, release and environments

Created the scripts for data relocation

Developed and established an external Node.js website with MongoDB backend

Consulting Release Manager via Open Systems Technologies at Barclays Capital

October 2009 - July 2011 (1 year 10 months)

Led 20 managers on a global team

Controlled program releases over 500+ servers

Coordinated daily workflow

Consulting Release Manager via Open Systems Technologies at Bank of America

February 2009 - October 2009 (9 months)

- # Provided end to end Release Management solutions for GMI Debt division of Bank of America (formerly Merrill Lynch)
- # Provided support for 50 developers across 3 big projects by managing a team of 5 Release Managers across US and India.
- # Introduced continuous build cycles to all projects using CruiseContol and CC.Net
- # Initiated strict Change Management procedures starting with planning of releases. Represented the project in companywide CAB meetings.
- # Provided a web based front end to the Release Management system using PHP.
- # Planned and deployed Business Continuity environments for all projects. Successfully completed all continuity tests within the allocated tier timings.
- # Planned and implemented strict branch/merge policy for supporting multiple streams of development for SDLC and Agile development.
- # Used Git for personal projects including the web front end I developed to automate deployments.

Consulting Release Manager via Open Systems Technologies at Bridgewater Associates

June 2008 - February 2009 (9 months)

- # Provided Release and Configuration management solutions for Client Services division
- # Used TeamCity, MSBuild and PowerShell to automate build and deployment for various projects.
- # Deployed various code metrics tools like NCover, NDepend, FXCop and Fitnesse to provide per build metrics.
- # Developed and implemented standardized policies for Release and Configuration management like Branch/ Merge, dependency management etc.
- # Developed and implemented policies for Change Management to asses Change risk across various environments and served as Change Management chair-person
- # Successfully migrated legacy builds from Nant and CC.Net to MSBuild and Teamcity
- # Wrote MSBuild plugin in C# to check MD5 checksum of build dependencies against a database with known signatures

Consulting Release Manager via Open Systems Technologies at Merrill Lynch

November 2006 - June 2008 (1 year 8 months)

- # Provided Release Management services to the GMI Debt division by managing 5 Release Managers.
- # Migrated code from legacy CVS to newer SVN systems for better management.

- # Managed progression of build artifacts across various environments including dev, QA, UAT and Prod
- # Automated builds using Teamcity for ready availability of build artifacts and to establish a continuous feedback loop.
- # Built deployment request system that tied into SVN and Teamcity to automate deployment.
- # Was also responsible for Configuration Management and managing various environments including QA, UAT and Production
- # Wrote miscellaneous utility scripts to ease day-to-day tasks like remote deployment, diffing jars etc.

Release Manager at Amaranth LLC

October 2004 - November 2006 (2 years 2 months)

- # Shared multiple roles including Release Manager, QA Engineer and Application Support
- # Was responsible for managing various environments for all projects across mixed platforms like Solaris, Linux and Windows
- # Spearheaded streamlining and automation of menial tasks.
- # Restructured integration, staging and Production environments which helped in managing code and configuration better
- # Performed app support duties for day-to-day running of core process of company and provided troubleshooting when errors occurred.
- # Provided 24/7 support to applications used by traders utilizing knowledge of Java, Tibco and ICE.
- # Developed web front end to automate release in test and integration environments.

Release Manager at UBS Investment Bank

December 2003 - October 2004 (11 months)

- # Worked as Release Manager for Equities division. Supported about 50 developers with daily release tasks.
- # Responsibly moved code between environment environments like Integration, QA, UAT and Prod while maintaining traceability to the source.
- # Designed and implemented policies for code management
- # Wrote scripts in Perl to perform code migration to ClearCase
- # Wrote a fully automated release process, which took inputs from a chat channel and deployed to any environment as long as approvals were given via chat.
- # Deployed a real-time replica of Clearcase server for Houston developers, which facilitated the development tasks for the remote team.
- # Wrote scripts to sanity check the repository, enforce checkin rules, monitor the replication and resolve any conflicts automatically.

Head of Network Admin at i-flex solutions

October 2001 - November 2003 (2 years 2 months)

- # Was deputed to New Jersey office for 4 months to build the infrastructure from scratch
- # Was involved in building the infrastructure of the Pune office from scratch with a team of three infrastructure engineers supporting 250+ users

- # Was involved in building the voice and data network, procurement of equipment, vendor interaction, data center setup and establishing connection to Citibank NA network.
- # After the infrastructure build out, lead a team of 11 infrastructure engineers to support the voice and data network, server and network infrastructure and the desktops.
- # Installed, configured and managed all the server and network equipment in the data center.
- # Provided IT support to local and remote teams.
- # Deployed a network of caching, fail-safe cluster of proxies that routed web traffic intelligently.

System Admin

2002 - 2002 (1 year)

- # Was responsible for network management including the external facing website
- # Configured and deployed virtualization using existing technologies like Virtuald, MySql and Apache JServ
- # Performed security analysis on the finished product
- # Configured the Intranet site for Oil and Natural gas Commission which included IPlanet suite of products and Cisco Routers
- # Configured fetchmail with spam filter and outgoing mail server.
- # Wrote Perl script to automatically configure mailbox for new users
- # Wrote a Perl script that managed two routing tables on a Linux box that acted as a router to switch traffic between two T1 lines based on availability.

System Admin

1999 - 2002 (4 years)

- # Managed a team that grew to the size of 50 consultants providing services in various system administration areas like Solaris, Networking, and Security etc.
- # Provided backend support to on-site consultants working on major projects in Fortune 100 companies in US
- # Created a division specializing in network security which provided security services to local and remote clients like security audits, penetration testing etc.
- # Created an R&D division to research various products and platforms like Linux Clustering, Firewalls etc.
- # Reported directly to the CEO and was responsible for the day-to-day working of the company as well as managing various in-flight projects.
- # Partnered with local vendors to provide packaged services under their brand which included ISP services, Data Center installation, Security Services, Server Configurations, Network configurations etc.

Education

University of Phoenix

MIS, Information Systems, 2011 - 2013

Center for Development of Advanced Computing

Diploma in Advanced Computing, Advanced Computing, 1998 - 1999

University of Mumbai

Bachelor of Science, Physics, 1994 - 1998

Nilesh Nimkar

DevOps Advocate, Cloud expert, Senior Release Engineer, IT Director/Lead

Nilesh.Nimkar@GMail.com



Contact Nilesh on LinkedIn